(peaceful guitar music)
[Boy] What?
The Super Scary Movie
series went up to Five?
Seven in fact!
For real?
Whoa! Then the seventh
one must be really out there!
Yeah!
It turned into a completely
different thing by Seven.
It's not just a parody anymore.
What kind of movie is it then?
[Junpei] Hmm...
Like a convoluted sitcom,
plus lineage horror, maybe?
[Friend] Huh? What do you means?
[Junpei] By a total fluke,
the grandchild of the
main character from One
ends up living in a shared house
with the grandchild
of the culprit from Two
and the grandchild of the
first person who died in Three.
But it turns out it's
a haunted house,
so they call in a spirit medium.
That's pretty much the plot.
Okay. Sounds like a bore.
[Junpei] It bored me to death!
So who would watch that?
There was one cool thing.
The guy from
five and six was in-
(door opens)
Huh? What are you doing in here?
Didn't I tell you this
room was ours now
and to stay the hell out of it?
(gasps) Yeah, well...
But you haven't been
using it for weeks, so I...
I just thought it
would be all right!
(slam)
(gasps)
[Itou] So...
So, well, I, um...
(slam)
(gasps)
Just get your asses out of
here already, you cockroaches!
Come on, Yoshino.
[Itou] Next time we
catch you in here,
we'll send you flying!
(phone beeps)
[Nishimura] Oh yeah, score!
Hey, Junpei, just forget it!
(sighs)
What now?
[Junpei] That belongs to me.
[Itou] So?
(tense music)
[Junpei] So...
move your foot.
[Friend] Junpei, just let it go!
No, this belongs to me.
Take your foot off of it.
(whimpering)
(slam)
-Oh damn!
-Oh shit!
(dramatic music)
(breathing heavily)
-Okay!
-I'm outta here!
Okay, okay, we're going!
(pats shoulder)
Close the door.
[Honda] Roger that.
(laughs)
(breathing heavily)
-(pounding)
-(grunting)
(Opening Theme Music)
(singing in Japanese)
(water dripping)
[Junpei] I wonder if
the first person to say
"the opposite of
fondness is indifference"
went to hell like
they should have.
Purposely treating people
with malice is never right.
A better choice would be
to just leave them alone.
"The opposite of
fondness is hate."
Japanese people love that idea.
They're proud to
take a simple answer
and make it complicated.
[Mahito] The man who coined
that phrase wasn't Japanese.
I'm talking about the
mistaken translation.
[Mahito] Hmm?
[Junpei] The original saying,
as it was first spoken
by some foreigner, was:
"the opposite of love
is indifference," right?
There are lots of
different definitions of love,
so it seems to me
that indifference
actually works as
an antonym there.
Yes, true.
But we generally don't use
the word "love" very much.
So I guess that's
why in this country,
it got changed to
"fondness" at some point.
Then that version spread
without any thought
as to whether the
opposing definitions...
of love and indifference
still held true.
Well, everyone
enjoys a little wordplay.
And after all, humans can't live
without making up
excuses for everything.
(eerie music)
What's this?
It was an experiment
to see just how large
I could make a single human.
I made the one you're holding
as an experiment to see
how small I could make them.
Are you saying...
this is...
a human?
[Mahito] Do corpses
bother you, Junpei?
I don't know.
If you had done this to
my mother, well then...
I might lose control
and end up hating you.
But I already know how
repulsive humans can be.
That's why I don't
expect much of anything
from other people.
Nor do I think much of it
when someone I don't know dies.
It's indifference.
That's the virtue one
ought to strive for.
Yet you want revenge...
despite that.
Do you see a conflict?
Between the two?
Do you believe human
beings have hearts?
Huh? Why, don't they?
[Mahito] No, they don't.
They have souls, but
souls aren't hearts.
That can't be right!
I'm the only
person in this world
who knows the
soul's composition.
After all, I change the
shape of other creatures
by making contact with them.
All emotions are the result
of the soul's metabolism.
They're far too
mechanical to call hearts.
People place too much
value on things they can't see.
I can see them, and
souls are no more special
than physical bodies.
They're just there.
Do you understand?
There's no value or
importance to life.
Life just continues its cycle,
same as the waters of the world.
That's true for both you and me.
Our lives are meaningless
and have no value.
And that's why we can
do anything we want.
We're free to live our
lives however we please.
(gurgling)
Don't let yourself get trapped
by some ideal
concept of indifference.
There's no need for
consistency in living your life.
Just as you eat
when you get hungry,
so it is that if
you hate someone
you can simply kill them.
I'll sanction you fully.
(crumbles)
(emotional music)
(birds whistling)
[Kiyotaka] There he is.
[Yuuji] Huh.
Where's his uniform?
It looks like he hasn't
been attending school
for some time.
Well I guess you could
say the same for me too.
So, hey, how's everyone doing?
(yelling)
[Man] Tuna!
From what I hear,
they're doing quite well.
So what do we do now?
We're going to use that.
Huh?
Is that a cursed spirit?
It's a fly-head,
alow-level curse
that doesn't even
qualify as a grade Four.
When there are no people around,
we'll release this
curse to attack him.
Huh?
[Kiyotaka] Then one of
four things will happen.
One, if he's a normal person
who can't even see curses,
you will please save him.
Two, if he can
perceive the curse
but has no means to
deal with it, then likewise...
save him please.
Afterwards we'll question
him about the theater incident.
Three, if he exorcizes
the fly head with jujutsu...
then we immediately
restrain him.
Restrain him how?
By whatever force necessary.
If it's all a misunderstanding,
we'll apologize after the fact.
However...
Four, if Junpei Yoshino
has potential equal
to a grade Two sorcerer...
then we retreat and
report to Nanami.
From what I've
seen, I'm thinking
I can just handle a grade Two.
Not in this case.
[Yuuji] Hm?
[Kiyotaka] Fushiguro
might have mentioned this
to you before.
Typically, cursed
spirits are assigned
to sorcerers of equal grade.
That means a grade Two
sorcerer would be expected
to beat grade
Two cursed spirits.
So a grade Two sorcerer
possesses strength
close to a grade
One cursed spirit.
Why the hell wasn't I ever told
something as important as that?
[Kiyotaka] Because
Gojou is irresponsible!
(sighs)
We'll get out and
walk from here.
I have to tell you
it feels like I'm the one
doing all the work here.
(suspenseful music)
(dripping)
If you plan to come out,
please hurry up and do so.
They may be disfigured
and beyond saving...
but murdering people
still makes me sick.
Ah, what a relief.
I'd be in trouble if
Satoru Gojou were here.
Although the experiment
won't really work
if you're too weak.
I hate putting in
overtime if I don't have to.
So let's finish this quickly.
(energetic music)
(laughing)
[Satoru] I'll murder you!
[Kento] They're similar.
They both have that same
picture-perfect frivolity
with the sinister
strength behind it.
(splashing)
(grunting)
(laughs)
Huh?
I blocked it with
cursed energy, I thought.
Was that your technique?
What do you mean?
I hate abstract questions
that leave interpretation
up to others.
That's good.
But you don't hate
chatting evidently.
Not at this time.
This cursed spirit
converses quite well.
Just like the two unregistered
special grades
in Gojou's report.
It would seem highly likely
that there's some connection.
[Mahito] Hey, tell me...
which do you think came
first, the soul or the body?
[Kento] Hm?
Come on. You know.
It's just like the age-old
chicken-or-the-egg question.
Which of them came first?
Do you think the soul
resides in the body,
or do you think it's
the other way around
and the body forms
around the soul?
[Kento] I suppose I
have to listen to this.
The former.
Uh-uh.
It's the second one.
The soul comes first and
so exists before the body.
The shape of the body is
therefore always determined
by the shape of the soul.
I'm not healing now.
I'm just maintaining the
shape of my own soul.
You understand now, don't you?
My technique is to make
contact with the soul,
and then alter its shape.
Idle Transfiguration!
(gasps)
I keep a human stockpile.
It's been difficult though.
Normal people die soon
after their shape is transfigured.
I wonder if jujutsu
sorcerers last longer.
It's 5:30 now, and I began
my day at 10:00 this morning,
so I'm quitting at 6:00,
regardless of
what that requires.
[Sotomura] Yoshino!
Huh?
Where were ya today?
(groans)
Missed you at school. You
shouldn't be skipping class.
Of course, sir. I know that.
Anyway, did you hear
about those theater murders?
It's all over the news.
Sayama, Nishimura
and Honda are all dead!
(gasps)
(cackling)
You were friends with all three
of those boys, weren't you?
They spent time with you
when you had no
other friends, right?
But you didn't go
to their funerals.
[Junpei] Friends?
Me...
and them?
He must be insane.
You teachers...
You graduate from school,
and then you go to work
in those same schools.
So you never actually
experience the real world, do you?
That's how we end up
with overgrown children
like you in charge, isn't it?
Here! Say "Ah"!
(cackles)
[Junpei] It's true of
every last one of them!
Smile! Say cheese!
[Mahito] You can
simply kill them.
I'll sanction you fully.
(gasps)
What in the world are you
mumbling about, Junpei?
Did self-isolation
fry your brain?
(laughs)
(gasps)
(dramatic music)
[Yuuji] Stop!
(yelling)
[Junpei] What the hell is that?
Whoa!
This guy...
can see the curse!
(shouts)
(grunts)
Ow! That freakin' hurt!
Look around.
Here we go, Itadori!
Time out! There's someone there!
Huh?
Oh, no!
That was close!
What's this? Where
did you come from?
Hey, I've got a few things
I'd like to ask you about.
Got a sec?
Uh, I was...
[Yuuji] Come with me.
[Junpei] That button!
[Sotomura] Hold on,
Junpei and I were
having a conversation!
Don't be rude!
Ah, well, this concerns
something rather important.
What's important?
You're just another stupid kid!
And what kind of uniform is-
(shouts)
(yells) Hey!
(gasps)
(yells)
What the hell do you
think you're doing, you brat?
Let go of my pants!
No, don't!
Stop! Get back here with those!
Come back! Wait!
(energetic music)
What was that all about?
Huh?
Okay, let's talk!
[Junpei] You went
around the block already?
That was fast!
Yeah.
You didn't have to
go to all that trouble.
You could have just
dragged me away.
[Yuuji] Yeah, sure, I
guess I could have.
But you hate that
guy, don't you?
Huh?
How did you...
Oh, just a hunch.
Or am I wrong?
[Junpei] No, you're not wrong.
You don't want someone you hate
hanging around outside
your house now do you?
So how 'bout we take a walk?
Sure.
(intense music)
(grunts)
Your speed's impressive.
(shouts)
This is so fun!
[Kento] So the person's
original mass is irrelevant
when it comes to
changing their shape.
Either way, it's a bad
match-up for my technique.
Please, help me!
There's nothing you can do
to save someone
once they're reshaped.
If they start to attack,
you must kill them.
It's better for the
victims that way.
Ah, yeah, sorry about that.
I had to really
practice a lot...
so they wouldn't die right
away when I changed their size.
And yet...
do they know?
I don't know precisely
how aware they are.
And as a result sometimes
their souls sweat like that one.
Don't let that worry you.
[Kento] I'm not
worried about it.
It's my policy not to bring
personal feelings into my work.
(laughing)
You suck at lying!
Your whole soul is trembling!
So you're...
what grade?
[Kento] Grade One.
No wonder you're strong.
You'll make the
perfect test subject.
Luck's really on my side.
I'm grateful.
(groaning)
Are you surprised my
speed suddenly increased?
The fact is I can alter the
shape of my own soul, too.
Jujutsu sorcerers can
protect their bodies
with cursed energy, but they
aren't protecting their souls.
For starters, you have to
be aware of your own soul.
It's not possible to
protect it if you're not.
But it looks to me like you
subconsciously covered your soul
somewhat with cursed energy.
If you hadn't done that you'd
already be under my control.
Though, once I touch
you a few more times
you will cease to
be human anymore!
(grunts)
I'm not letting you go!
Was that it, grade One sorcerer?
You did well running around,
but you're at your
limit now, aren't you?
(ticking)
(sighs)
Unfortunately...
[Mahito] What?
His cursed energy's increasing?
Thanks to you...
I'm going to have
to go into overtime.
(Closing Theme Music)
(singing in Japanese)
[Group] Juju Stroll!
(light percussive music)
Fushiguro!
Seen my uniform jacket?
I haven't.
Whoa, that's so weird!
I left it right here.
Oh!
Hey Panda?
Have you seen my
jacket anywhere?
Hm...
No, sorry...
Okay...
I wonder where it
could have gone.
-(shouts)
-(grunts)
Hey! My skirt's not here
either, you clothing klepto!
Now you've gone too far!
[Toge] Mustard leaf!
(snarling)
[Nobara] You're both trash!
Bonito flakes!
[Megumi] What am I looking at?
Huh?
What the?
This is Maki's skirt!
Hey, check me out!
I'm Nobara Kuuugisaki!
(laughing)
(dramatic music)